

Interests

Scientific Research: I am interested in research (and teaching) in computer science, mathematics, economics, synthetic biology and neuroscience.

Public Policy: I want to use my analytical skills to help improve decision-making, especially that pertaining to government policy on technology.

Communication: I enjoy non-fiction writing, especially figuring out the analogies and methods that work best at communicating technical material to an unfamiliar audience.

Education

University of Oxford

2020-present

Oxford

Inaugural Stephen Cameron Scholar at Keble College · Departmental Fellowship

Indian Institute of Science

2016-2020

Bangalore

First Class with Distinction · KVPY Fellow · CGPA: 9/10

B.S. (Research) in Mathematics

DPhil in Computer Science

Publications

How fast can you escape a compact polytope?: With Engel Lefaucheux, Joël Ouaknine and James Worrell. Accepted to **STACS 2020.** (link)

Graduate-Level Coursework

- o Mathematics: Measure Theory, Linear Algebra, Abstract Algebra, Ordinary Differential Equations, Topology, Matrix Analysis and Positivity
- Computer Science: Machine Learning, Practical Data Science, Foundations of Data Science & High Dimensional Probability, Automata Theory and Computability, Deep Learning Theory and Practice (IISc & Microsoft Research), Digital Epidemiology

Experience

Innovate India Drug Discovery Hackathon 2020

July 2020-present

ddhackiisc

Collaborating with a team of biochemists in a Govt of India project competition to develop machine learning models to identify drugs with liver toxicity and generate promising antiviral molecules using GANs and variational autoencoders

Monsoon Math Camp April 2020

IISc, MIT, GMU undergraduates

Helped organize a online mathematics camp for talented Indian high-schoolers, aiming to introduce them to advanced matheamtical topics not covered in the school or university curriculum.

Bachelor Thesis: Error-Prone Model Learning

January-June 2020

IISc

Worked on speeding up classical automata learning techniques with recurrent neural networks. Experimental work joint with Alvin George. Advised by Deepak D'Souza and Chiranjeeb Bhattacharya (IISc CSA) and Sriram Rajamani (Microsoft Research)

Machine Learning Experiment Contractor and Analyst

July 2019-February 2020

Ought, San Francisco (Remote)

Participated in experiments and ran analyses for ought.org, a research lab aiming to train machine learning systems to answer complex and open-ended questions

MPI-SWS Summer Internship

May - July 2019

Max Planck Institute for Software Systems, Saarbrucken

Worked on applications of continuous linear dynamical systems to hybrid automata with Prof. Joël Ouaknine and Prof. James Worrell (Oxford CS)

Human-Aligned AI Summer School

July 2019

Faculty of Mathematics and Physics, Charles University, Prague

Interacted with researchers from DeepMind, OpenAI, Oxford and UC Berkeley studying alignment of advanced AI agents

European Summer Program on Rationality

August 2017

King's College London

Invited back to ESPR on a full scholarship as a Junior Counselor, after attending as a student in 2016. Studied functional programming, deep learning and statistical inference, guided younger students.

Sakura Japan-Asia Youth Exchange in Science

May 2015

Kyoto University and Tokyo University of Science

Worked on polymer chemistry experiments under Nobel laureate Prof. Hideki Shirakawa.

Selected Awards and Honours

<u> </u>	
International Genetically Engineered Machine Competition (iGEM) Gold Medallist Gold Medal + Best Hardware Nomination for iFLOAT ('17), Gold Medal for PhageShift ('18)	2017 and 2018 <i>Boston</i>
iGEM Foundation National Bal Shree Awardee in Creative Scientific Innovation	2012
1 of 8 Science Awardees that year Ministry of HRD, Government of India	Delhi
Kishore Vaigyanik Protsahan Yojana (KVPY) Fellowship	2014
All India Rank 57 (SA) out of \sim 50,000 candidates	Bangalore
Indian Institute of Science	
Microsoft Research Fellow (declined)	2020
Offered an RF position working with Neeraj Kayal and Ankit Garg Microsoft Research Bangalore	Bangalore
IIT-Bombay Mathematics Olympiad	2015
2nd Place in India	Mumbai
Indian Institute of Technology, Powai	
National College Ultimate Championship	2018
Captained IISc to 4th place in India at Ultimate Frisbee Nationals Ashoka University and Ultimate Players Association of India	Delhi

Selected Research and Writing

Adversarial Examples for CNNs: Analysed Wasserstein distance based approaches to building robust image classifiers. With Gaurang Sriramanan. Final project for Deep Learning: Theory and Practice. (link)

Resistance: Tales from A Post-Antibiotic World: Edited an anthology of short fiction themed around antibiotic resistance. 96pp. Published by IIScPress (2019).

Functional Programming in Scala: Reading project, Summer-Winter 2018. Studied functional programming and homotopy type theory with applications to natural language processing of mathematical text under Prof. Siddhartha Gadgil, Math, IISc.

GCODe: Engineering project, Summer-Fall 2017. Designed an automated process to speed up synthetic biology experiments as part of iFLOAT, the IISc iGEM 2017 project. Wrote the wiki at http://2017.igem.org/Team: IISc-Bangalore/Hardware.

Skills

- Technical and creative writing (340/340 GRE)
- o Programming: Python, C++ (basic), Haskell (basic)
- o Leadership: City-wide Quiz Club Co-founder and College Ultimate Frisbee Team Captain
- o Public Speaking: Invited motivational speaker